tanzania-adventure.com 2018-11-27

# Privacy Policy - Tanzania Adventure

## Privacy policy

This Privacy Policy clarifies the nature, scope and purpose of the processing of personal data (hereinafter referred to as “Data”) within our online offering and the related websites, features and content, as well as external online presence, e.g. our social media profiles on. (collectively referred to as “online offer”). With regard to the terminology used, e.g. “Processing” or “Responsible”, we refer to the definitions in Article 4 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

#### Responsible

Tanzania (2000) Adventure  
P.O. box 10370  
Arusha, Tanzania  
Director:Gibson Blasius Meiseyeki  
Email: info@tanzania-adventure.com  
Imprint:[ https://tanzania-adventure.com/imprint](https://tanzania-adventure.com/imprint/)

#### Types of processed data:

– Inventory data (e.g., names, addresses).  
– contact information (e.g., e-mail, phone numbers).  
– content data (e.g., text input, photographs, videos).  
– usage data (e.g., websites visited, interest in content, access times).  
– Meta / communication data (e.g., device information, IP addresses).

#### Categories of affected persons

Visitors and users of the online offer (hereinafter we refer to the affected persons as “users”).

#### Purpose of processing

– Provision of the online offer, its functions and contents.  
– Answering contact requests and communicating with users.  
– Safety measures.  
– Reach Measurement / Marketing

#### Used terms

“Personal data” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (hereinafter the “data subject”); a natural person is considered as identifiable, which can be identified directly or indirectly, in particular by means of assignment to an identifier such as a name, to an identification number, to location data, to an online identifier (eg cookie) or to one or more special features, that express the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of this natural person.

“Processing” means any process performed with or without the aid of automated procedures or any such process associated with personal data. The term goes far and includes virtually every handling of data.

“Responsible person” means the natural or legal person, public authority, body or body that decides, alone or in concert with others, on the purposes and means of processing personal data.

#### Relevant legal bases

In accordance with Art. 13 GDPR, we inform you about the legal basis of our data processing. Unless the legal basis in the data protection declaration is mentioned, the following applies: The legal basis for obtaining consent is Article 6 (1) lit. a and Art. 7 GDPR, the legal basis for the processing for the performance of our services and the execution of contractual measures as well as the response to inquiries is Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR, the legal basis for processing in order to fulfill our legal obligations is Art. 6 (1) lit. c GDPR, and the legal basis for processing in order to safeguard our legitimate interests is Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. In the event that vital interests of the data subject or another natural person require the processing of personal data, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. d GDPR as legal basis.

#### Collaboration with processors and third parties

If, in the context of our processing, we disclose data to other persons and companies (contract processors or third parties), transmit them to them or otherwise grant access to the data, this will only be done on the basis of a legal permission (eg if a transmission of the data to third parties, as required by payment service providers, pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR to fulfill the contract), you have consented to a legal obligation or based on our legitimate interests (eg the use of agents, webhosters, etc.).  
If we commission third parties to process data on the basis of a so-called “contract processing contract”, this is done on the basis of Art. 28 GDPR.

#### Transfers to third countries

If we process data in a third country (ie outside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA)) or in the context of the use of third party services or disclosure or transmission of data to third parties, this will only be done if it is to fulfill our (pre) contractual obligations, on the basis of your consent, on the basis of a legal obligation or on the basis of our legitimate interests. Subject to legal or contractual permissions, we process or have the data processed in a third country only in the presence of the special conditions of Art. 44 et seq. GDPR. That the processing is e.g. on the basis of specific guarantees, such as the officially recognized level of data protection (eg for the US through the Privacy Shield) or compliance with officially recognized special contractual obligations (so-called “standard contractual clauses”).

#### Rights of data subjects

You have the right to ask for confirmation as to whether the data in question is being processed and for information about this data as well as for further information and a copy of the data in accordance with Art. 15 GDPR.

You have accordingly. Art. 16 GDPR the right to demand the completion of the data concerning you or the correction of the incorrect data concerning you.

In accordance with Art. 17 GDPR, they have the right to demand that the relevant data be deleted immediately or, alternatively, to require a restriction of the processing of data in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR.

You have the right to demand that the data relating to you, which you have provided to us, be obtained in accordance with Art. 20 GDPR and request their transmission to other persons responsible.

You have according to Art. 77 GDPR the right to file a complaint with the competent supervisory authority.

#### Withdrawal

You have the right to grant consent in accordance with. Art. 7 para. 3 GDPR with effect for the future

#### Right to object

You can object to the future processing of your data in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR at any time. The objection may in particular be made against processing for direct marketing purposes.

#### Cookies and right to object in direct mail

“Cookies” are small files that are stored on users’ computers. Different information can be stored within the cookies. A cookie is primarily used to store the information about a user (or the device on which the cookie is stored) during or after his visit to an online offer. Temporary cookies, or “session cookies” or “transient cookies”, are cookies that are deleted after a user leaves an online service and closes his browser. In such a cookie, e.g. the contents of a shopping cart are stored in an online store or a login jam. The term “permanent” or “persistent” refers to cookies that remain stored even after the browser has been closed. Thus, e.g. the login status will be saved if users visit it after several days. Likewise, in such a cookie the interests of the users can be stored, which are used for range measurement or marketing purposes. A “third-party cookie” refers to cookies that are offered by providers other than the person who manages the online offer (otherwise, if it is only their cookies, this is called “first-party cookies”).

We can use temporary and permanent cookies and clarify this in the context of our privacy policy.

If users do not want cookies stored on their computer, they will be asked to disable the option in their browser’s system settings. Saved cookies can be deleted in the system settings of the browser. The exclusion of cookies can lead to functional restrictions of this online offer.

A general contradiction to the use of cookies used for online marketing purposes can be found in a variety of services, especially in the case of tracking, via the US website <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> or the EU site <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/> be explained. Furthermore, the storage of cookies can be achieved by switching them off in the settings of the browser. Please note that not all features of this online offer may be used.

#### Deletion of data

The data processed by us are deleted or limited in their processing in accordance with Articles 17 and 18 GDPR. Unless explicitly stated in this privacy policy, the data stored by us are deleted as soon as they are no longer required for their purpose and the deletion does not conflict with any statutory storage requirements. Unless the data is deleted because it is required for other and legitimate purposes, its processing will be restricted. That The data is blocked and not processed for other purposes. This applies, for example for data that must be kept for commercial or tax reasons.

According to legal requirements in Germany, the storage takes place in particular for 6 years pursuant to § 257 paragraph 1 HGB (trading books, inventories, opening balance sheets, annual accounts, trade letters, accounting documents, etc.) and for 10 years in accordance with § 147 Abs. 1 AO (books, records , Management reports, accounting documents, trade and business letters, documents relevant to taxation, etc.).

According to legal regulations in Austria the storage takes place especially for 7 years according to § 132 paragraph 1 BAO (accounting documents, receipts / invoices, accounts, receipts, business papers, statement of income and expenses, etc.), for 22 years in connection with real estate and for 10 years in the case of documents relating to electronically supplied services, telecommunications, broadcasting and television services provided to non-entrepreneurs in EU Member States and for which the Mini-One-Stop-Shop (MOSS) is used.

#### Business-related processing

In addition we process  
– contract data (e.g., subject, term, customer category).  
– Payment data (e.g., bank details, payment history)  
from our customers, prospects and business partners for the purpose of providing contractual services, service and customer care, marketing, advertising and market research.

#### Hosting

The hosting services we use are for the purpose of providing the following services: infrastructure and platform services, computing capacity, storage and database services, security and technical maintenance services we use to operate this online service.

Here we, or our hosting provider, process inventory data, contact data, content data, contract data, usage data, meta and communication data of customers, interested parties and visitors to this online offer on the basis of our legitimate interests in an efficient and secure provision of this online offer acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR i.V.m. Art. 28 GDPR (conclusion of contract processing contract).

#### Collection of access data and log files

We, or our hosting provider, collects on the basis of our legitimate interests within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR Data on every access to the server on which this service is located (so-called server log files). The access data includes name of the retrieved web page, file, date and time of retrieval, amount of data transferred, message about successful retrieval, browser type and version, the user’s operating system, referrer URL (the previously visited page), IP address and the requesting provider.

Logfile information is stored for security purposes (for example, to investigate abusive or fraudulent activities) for a maximum of 7 days and then deleted. Data whose further retention is required for evidential purposes shall be exempted from the cancellation until final clarification of the incident.

#### Provision of contractual services

We process inventory data (e.g., names and addresses as well as contact information of users), contract data (e.g., services used, names of contacts, payment information) for the purpose of fulfilling our contractual obligations and services in accordance with Art. Art. 6 para. 1 lit b. GDPR. The entries marked as obligatory in online forms are required for the conclusion of the contract.

As part of the use of our online services, we store the IP address and the time of each user action. The storage is based on our legitimate interests, as well as the user’s protection against misuse and other unauthorized use. A transfer of these data to third parties does not take place, unless it is necessary for the prosecution of our claims or there is a legal obligation in accordance with. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR.

We process usage data (e.g., the visited web pages of our online offering, interest in our products) and content data (e.g., entries in the contact form or user profile) for advertising purposes in a user profile to inform the user e.g. To display product instructions based on their previously used services.

The deletion of the data takes place after expiration of legal warranty and comparable obligations, the necessity of the storage of the data is checked every three years; in the case of legal archiving obligations, the deletion takes place after its expiration. Information in the customer’s account remains until it is deleted.

#### Administration, financial accounting, office organization, contact management

We process data in the context of administrative tasks and organization of our business, financial accounting and compliance with legal obligations, such as archiving. We process the same data that we process in the course of rendering our contractual services. The processing principles are Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c. GDPR, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR. The processing affects customers, prospects, business partners and website visitors. The purpose and interest in processing lies in administration, financial accounting, office organization, data archiving, that is, tasks that serve to maintain our business, perform our duties and provide our services. The deletion of the data in terms of contractual performance and contractual communication corresponds to the information provided in these processing activities.

We disclose or transmit data to the financial administration, consultants, such as tax accountants or auditors, and other fee agents and payment service providers.

Furthermore, based on our business interests, we store information about suppliers, promoters and other business partners, e.g. for later contact. We generally store this majority of company-related data permanently.

#### Business analysis and market research

In order to operate our business economically, to be able to recognize market trends, customer and user requirements, we analyze the data we have on business transactions, contracts, inquiries, etc. We process stock data, communication data, contract data, payment data, usage data, metadata on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR, whereby the persons affected include customers, prospects, business partners, visitors and users of the online offer.

The analyzes are carried out for the purpose of business analysis, marketing and market research. In doing so, we can display the profiles of the registered users with indications e.g. to consider their purchase transactions. The analyzes serve us to increase the user-friendliness, the optimization of our offer and the business economics. The analyzes are for us alone and will not be disclosed externally unless they are anonymous, aggregated value analyzes.

If these analyzes or profiles are personal, they will be deleted or anonymised upon termination of the users, otherwise after two years from the conclusion of the contract. Incidentally, the overall business analyzes and general trend provisions are created anonymously if possible.

#### User registration

Users can optionally create a user account. As part of the registration, the necessary mandatory information is communicated to the users. The data entered during registration will be used for the purpose of using the offer. Users may be informed by e-mail about offer or registration-related information, such as changes in the scope of the offer or technical circumstances. If users have terminated their user account, their data will be deleted with regard to the user account, subject to their retention is for commercial or tax law reasons according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR necessary. It is the responsibility of the users to secure their data upon termination before the end of the contract. We are entitled to irretrievably delete all user data stored during the term of the contract.

In the context of the use of our registration and registration functions as well as the use of user accounts, the IP address and the time of the respective user action will be saved. The storage is based on our legitimate interests, as well as the user’s protection against misuse and other unauthorized use. A transfer of these data to third parties does not take place, unless it is necessary for the prosecution of our claims or there is a legal obligation in accordance with. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR. The IP addresses will be anonymized or deleted after 7 days at the latest.

#### Contact

When contacting us (for example, by contact form, e-mail, telephone or via social media) the information of the user to process the contact request and its processing in accordance with. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR processed. User information can be stored in a Customer Relationship Management System (“CRM System”) or comparable request organization.

We delete the requests, if they are no longer required. We check the necessity every two years; Furthermore, the legal archiving obligations apply.

#### Comments and posts

If users leave comments or other contributions, their IP addresses are based on our legitimate interests within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. GDPR stored for 7 days. This is for our own safety, if someone leaves illegal content in comments and contributions (insults, prohibited political propaganda, etc.). In this case, we ourselves can be prosecuted for the comment or post and are therefore interested in the identity of the author.

#### Comment subscriptions

The follow-up comments may be made by users with their consent in accordance with. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR be subscribed. Users will receive a confirmation email to verify that they own the email address they entered. Users can unsubscribe from ongoing comment subscriptions at any time. The confirmation email will contain notes on the revocation options. For the purpose of proving the consent of the users, we store the logon deadline along with the IP address of the users and delete this information when users log out of the subscription.

You can terminate the receipt of our subscriptions at any time, ie. Revoke your consent. We may save the submitted email addresses for up to three years based on our legitimate interests before we delete them to provide prior consent. The processing of this data is limited to the purpose of a possible defense against claims. An individual request for cancellation is possible at any time, provided that at the same time the former existence of a consent is confirmed.

#### Get profile pictures from Gravatar

We use the Gravatar service of Automattic Inc., 60 29th Street # 343, San Francisco, CA 94110, USA, within our online offering and specifically on the blog.  
Gravatar is a service that allows users to log in and submit profile pictures and their email addresses. If users with the respective e-mail address on other online sites (especially in blogs) leave posts or comments, so their profile pictures can be displayed next to the posts or comments. For this purpose, the e-mail address communicated by the users to Gravatar is transmitted encrypted in order to check whether a profile is stored for it. This is the sole purpose of sending the e-mail address and it will not be used for other purposes, but will be deleted afterwards.  
The use of Gravatar is based on our legitimate interests within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR, because with the help of Gravatar we offer the post and comment writers the opportunity to personalize their posts with a profile picture.  
Automattic is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000CbqcAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000CbqcAAC&status=Active)).

By displaying the images, Gravatar has learned the IP address of the users, as this is necessary for communication between a browser and an online service. For more information about Gravatar’s collection and use of data, see the Automattic Privacy Notice: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>.

If users do not want a user picture linked to their email address on Gravatar to appear in the comments, they should use a non-Gravatar email address to comment. We also point out that it is also possible to use an anonymous or even no e-mail address if the users do not want their own e-mail address to be sent to Gravatar. Users can completely prevent the transfer of data by not using our commenting system.

#### Newsletter (Germany)

With the following information we inform you about the contents of our newsletter as well as the registration, dispatch and statistical evaluation procedures as well as your right of objection. By subscribing to our newsletter, you agree to the receipt and the procedures described.  
Content of the newsletter: We send newsletters, e-mails and other electronic notifications with advertising information (hereinafter “newsletter”) only with the consent of the recipient or a legal permission. Insofar as the contents of a newsletter are concretely described, they are authoritative for the consent of the users. Incidentally, our newsletter contains information about our services and us.  
Double opt-in and logging: Registration for our newsletter is done in a so-called double-opt-in procedure. That After registration, you will receive an e-mail asking you to confirm your registration. This confirmation is necessary so that nobody can register with external e-mail addresses. The registration for the newsletter will be logged in order to prove the registration process according to the legal requirements. This includes the storage of the login and the confirmation time, as well as the IP address. Likewise, changes to your data stored with the shipping service provider will be logged.

Credentials: To subscribe to the newsletter, it is sufficient to provide your e-mail address. Optionally, we ask you to give a name in the newsletter for personal address.

Germany: The dispatch of the newsletter and the associated performance measurement is based on the consent of the recipient gem. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a, Art. 7 GDPR in connection with § 7 Abs. 2 Nr. 3 UWG or on the basis of the legal permission according to Art. § 7 Abs. 3 UWG.

The logging of the registration process is based on our legitimate interests in accordance with. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. Our interest lies in the use of a user-friendly and secure newsletter system, which serves both our business interests and the expectations of the users and also allows us to prove our consent.

Termination / Revocation – You may terminate the receipt of our newsletter at any time, ie. Revoke your consent. A link to cancel the newsletter can be found at the end of each newsletter. We may save the submitted email addresses for up to three years based on our legitimate interests before we delete them to provide prior consent. The processing of this data is limited to the purpose of a possible defense against claims. An individual request for cancellation is possible at any time, provided that at the same time the former existence of a consent is confirmed.

#### Newsletter (Austria)

With the following information we inform you about the contents of our newsletter as well as the registration, dispatch and statistical evaluation procedures as well as your right of objection. By subscribing to our newsletter, you agree to the receipt and the procedures described.  
Content of the newsletter: We send newsletters, e-mails and other electronic notifications with advertising information (hereinafter “newsletter”) only with the consent of the recipient or a legal permission. Insofar as the contents of a newsletter are concretely described, they are authoritative for the consent of the users. Incidentally, our newsletter contains information about our services and us.  
Double opt-in and logging: Registration for our newsletter is done in a so-called double-opt-in procedure. That After registration, you will receive an e-mail asking you to confirm your registration. This confirmation is necessary so that nobody can register with external e-mail addresses. The registration for the newsletter will be logged in order to prove the registration process according to the legal requirements. This includes the storage of the login and the confirmation time, as well as the IP address. Likewise, changes to your data stored with the shipping service provider will be logged.

Credentials: To subscribe to the newsletter, it is sufficient to provide your e-mail address. Optionally, we ask you to give a name in the newsletter for personal address.

The dispatch of the newsletter and the related performance measurement is based on the consent of the recipient gem. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a, Art. 7 GDPR i.V.m. § 107 Abs. 2 TKG or on the basis of the legal permission acc. Section 107 (2) and the like 3 TKG.  
The logging of the registration process is based on our legitimate interests in accordance with. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. Our interest lies in the use of a user-friendly and secure newsletter system, which serves both our business interests and the expectations of the users and also allows us to prove our consent.

Termination / Revocation – You may terminate the receipt of our newsletter at any time, ie. Revoke your consent. A link to cancel the newsletter can be found at the end of each newsletter. We may save the submitted email addresses for up to three years based on our legitimate interests before we delete them to provide prior consent. The processing of this data is limited to the purpose of a possible defense against claims. An individual request for cancellation is possible at any time, provided that at the same time the former existence of a consent is confirmed.

#### Newsletter – service provider

The newsletter is sent by the service provider:

Elastic Email – Geographical Media Inc.  
Site 270 RR2  
T0E0H0 Carvel  
Alberta, Canada

You can view the privacy policy of the service provider here: <https://elasticemail.com/resources/usage-policies/privacy-policy/>. The service provider is based on our legitimate interests acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR and a contract processing agreement acc. Art. 28 (3) sentence 1 GDPR.  
The service provider may use the data of the recipients in pseudonymous form, i. without assignment to a user, to optimize or improve their own services, e.g. for the technical optimization of dispatching and the presentation of newsletters or for statistical purposes. However, the service provider does not use the data of our newsletter recipients to address them themselves or to pass the data on to third parties.

#### Newsletter – Tracking

The newsletters contain a so-called “web-beacon”, i. a pixel-sized file that is retrieved from the server when opening the newsletter from our server, or if we use a shipping service provider. This call will initially collect technical information, such as information about the browser and your system, as well as your IP address and time of retrieval.

This information is used to improve the technical performance of services based on their specifications or audience and their reading habits, based on their locations (which can be determined using the IP address) or access times. Statistical surveys also include determining if the newsletters will be opened, when they will be opened and which links will be clicked. For technical reasons, this information can be assigned to the individual newsletter recipients. However, it is neither our goal nor, if used, that of the shipping service provider to observe individual users. The evaluations serve us much more to recognize the reading habits of our users and to adapt our content to them or to send different content according to the interests of our users.

#### Google Analytics

Based on our legitimate interests (i.e., interest in the analysis, optimization, and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. GDPR), Google Analytics uses a web analytics service provided by Google LLC (“Google”). Google uses cookies. The information generated by the cookie about the use of the online offer by the users are usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)).

Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate the use of our online offer by users, to compile reports on the activities within this online offer and to provide us with further services related to the use of this online offer and the internet usage. In this case, pseudonymous usage profiles of the users can be created from the processed data.

We only use Google Analytics with activated IP anonymization. This means that the IP address of the users will be shortened by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there.

The IP address submitted by the user’s browser will not be merged with other data provided by Google. Users can prevent the storage of cookies by setting their browser software accordingly; Users may also prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookie and related to its use of the online offer and the processing of such data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

For more information about Google’s data usage, hiring and opt-out options, please visit Google’s websites: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners> (“Google’s use of your data when you use websites or apps our partners “), <http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads> (” Use of data for promotional purposes “), <http://www.google.com/settings/ads> (” Managing information that Google uses, to show you advertising “).

Disable Google Analytics

#### Google Re / marketing services

On the basis of our legitimate interests (ie interest in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. GDPR) we use the marketing and remarketing services (“Google Marketing Services “), LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, (” Google “).

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)).

Google Marketing Services allows us to better target advertisements for and on our website so that we only present ads to users that potentially match their interests. If a user e.g. Showing ads for products he’s been interested in on other websites is called remarketing. For these purposes, when Google and our other websites accessing Google Marketing Services are directly accessed by Google, a code will be executed by Google and so-called (re) marketing tags (invisible graphics or code, also called “Web Beacons “) incorporated into the website. With their help, the user is provided with an individual cookie, i. a small file is saved (instead of cookies, comparable technologies can also be used). The cookies can be set by different domains, including google.com, doubleclick.net, invitemedia.com, admeld.com, googlesyndication.com or googleadservices.com. In this file is noted which web pages the user visited, for what content he is interested and what offers he has clicked, as well as technical information about the browser and operating system, referring web pages, visit time and other information on the use of the online offer. The IP address of the users is also recorded, whereby in the context of Google Analytics we announce that the IP address is shortened within member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area and only in exceptional cases to one Google server in the US is transmitted and shortened there. The IP address will not be merged with data of the user within other offers from Google. The above information may also be linked by Google with such information from other sources. If the user then visits other websites, they can be displayed according to his interests, the ads tailored to him.

The data of the users are pseudonym processed in the context of the Google marketing services. That Google stores and processes e.g. not the name or e-mail address of the users, but processes the relevant data cookie-related within pseudonymous user profiles. That from the perspective of Google, the ads are not managed and displayed to a specifically identified person, but to the cookie owner, regardless of who that cookie owner is. This does not apply if a user has explicitly allowed Google to process the data without this pseudonymization. The information collected about users through Google Marketing Services is transmitted to Google and stored on Google’s servers in the United States.

Among the Google marketing services we use is u.a. the online advertising program “Google AdWords”. In the case of Google AdWords, each advertiser receives a different “conversion cookie”. Cookies can not be tracked through AdWords advertisers’ websites. The information collected through the cookie is used to generate conversion statistics for AdWords advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. Advertisers will see the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a conversion tracking tag page. However, they do not receive information that personally identifies users.

We can incorporate third-party ads based on the Google AdSense marketing service. AdSense uses cookies that enable Google and its affiliate sites to serve ads based on users’ visits to this site or other sites on the Internet.

In addition, we may use the “Google Tag Manager” to integrate and manage the Google Analytics and Marketing Services on our website.

For more information about Google’s data usage for marketing, see the overview page: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads>, Google’s Privacy Policy located at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy> available.

If you wish to opt-out of interest-based advertising through Google Marketing Services, you can take advantage of Google’s recruitment and opt-out options: <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences>.

#### Facebook Pixels, Custom Audiences and Facebook Conversion

Within our online offer is due to our legitimate interests in analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer and for these purposes, the so-called “Facebook pixel” of the social network Facebook, by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025 , USA, or, if you are located in the EU, Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbor, Dublin 2, Ireland (“Facebook”).

Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active)).

With the help of the Facebook pixel, it is on the one hand possible for Facebook to determine the visitors to our online offer as a target group for the display of advertisements (so-called “Facebook ads”). Accordingly, we use the Facebook Pixel to display the Facebook Ads we have been sent only to those Facebook users who have shown an interest in our online offer or who have certain features (eg interests in certain topics or products visited by them) Web pages determined), which we transmit to Facebook (so-called “Custom Audiences”). With the help of the Facebook pixel, we also want to make sure that our Facebook ads are in line with the potential interest of users and are not annoying. With the help of the Facebook pixel we can also understand the effectiveness of the Facebook ads for statistical and market research purposes, in which we see whether users were redirected to our website after clicking on a Facebook ad (so-called “conversion”).

The processing of the data by Facebook is part of Facebook’s data usage policy. Accordingly, general notes on how to display Facebook Ads, in Facebook’s Data Usage Policy: https://www.facebook.com/policy.php. For specific information and details about the Facebook Pixel and how it works, visit the help section of Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/business/help/651294705016616>.

You may object to the capture by the Facebook Pixel and use of your data to display Facebook Ads. To set which types of ads you see within Facebook, you can go to the page set up by Facebook and follow the instructions for the usage-based advertising settings: <https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads>. The settings are platform independent, i. they are adopted for all devices, such as desktop computers or mobile devices.

You can also use the Cookies for distance measurement and promotional purposes via the deactivation page of the Network Advertising Initiative (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/>) and in addition the US website (<http://www.aboutads.info/choices>) or the European website (<http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices/>).

#### Online presence in social media

We maintain online presence within social networks and platforms in order to communicate with customers, prospects and users active there and to inform them about our services. When calling the respective networks and platforms, the terms and conditions and the data processing guidelines apply to their respective operators.

Unless otherwise stated in our Privacy Policy, we process users’ data as long as they communicate with us within social networks and platforms, e.g. Write posts on our online presence or send us messages.

#### Integration of services and contents of third parties

Based on our legitimate interests (ie interest in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. GDPR), we make use of content or services offered by third-party providers in order to provide their content and services Services, such as Include videos or fonts (collectively referred to as “content”).

This always presupposes that the third-party providers of this content perceive the IP address of the users, since they could not send the content to their browser without the IP address. The IP address is therefore required for the presentation of this content. We endeavor to use only content whose respective providers use the IP address solely for the delivery of the content. Third parties may also use so-called pixel tags (invisible graphics, also referred to as “web beacons”) for statistical or marketing purposes. The “pixel tags” can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on the pages of this website. The pseudonymous information may also be stored in cookies on the user’s device and may include, but is not limited to, technical information about the browser and operating system, referring web pages, visit time, and other information regarding the use of our online offer.

#### Vimeo

We can embed the videos of the Vimeo platform of Vimeo Inc., Attention: Legal Department, 555 West 18th Street New York, New York 10011, USA. Privacy Policy: <https://vimeo.com/privacy>.

#### Youtube

We embed the videos on the YouTube platform of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.  
Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>[  
](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)Opt-out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

#### Google Maps

We include maps from the Google Maps service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.  
Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>  
Oopt-out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

#### Google fonts

We integrate the fonts ( “Google Fonts”) the provider Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, one.  
Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>[  
](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)Opt-out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

#### Google ReCaptcha

We bind the function to detect bots, e.g. when typing in online forms ( “ReCaptcha”) the provider Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, one. Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>, opt-out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

#### Use of Facebook social plugins

Based on our legitimate interests (ie interest in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) f. GDPR) we use social plugins (“plugins”) of the social network facebook.com, which operated by Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbor, Dublin 2, Ireland (“Facebook”). The plugins can represent interaction elements or content (eg videos, graphics or text contributions) and can be recognized by one of the Facebook logos (white “f” on blue tile, the terms “Like”, “Like” or a “thumbs up” sign ) or are marked with the addition “Facebook Social Plugin”. The list and appearance of Facebook Social Plugins can be viewed here: <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>.

Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active)).

When a user invokes a feature of this online offering that includes such a plugin, their device establishes a direct connection to the Facebook servers. The content of the plugin is transmitted by Facebook directly to the device of the user and incorporated by him into the online offer. In the process, user profiles can be created from the processed data. We therefore have no influence on the amount of data that Facebook collects with the help of this plugin and therefore informs the users according to our knowledge.

By integrating the plugins, Facebook receives the information that a user has accessed the corresponding page of the online offer. If the user is logged in to Facebook, Facebook can assign the visit to his Facebook account. If users interact with the plugins, for example, press the Like button or leave a comment, the information is transmitted from your device directly to Facebook and stored there. If a user is not a member of Facebook, there is still the possibility that Facebook will find out and save their IP address. According to Facebook, only an anonymous IP address is stored in Germany.

The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook, as well as the related rights and setting options for protecting the privacy of users, can be found in Facebook’s privacy policy: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/> ,

If a user is a Facebook member and does not want Facebook to collect data about him via this online offer and link it to his member data stored on Facebook, he must log out of Facebook and delete his cookies before using our online offer. Other settings and inconsistencies regarding the use of data for advertising purposes are possible within the Facebook profile settings: <https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads> or via the US-American site <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> or the EU page <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>. The settings are platform independent, which menas they are adopted for all devices, such as desktop computers or mobile devices.

#### Twitter

Within our online offering, features and content of the Twitter service offered by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA, may be incorporated. For this, e.g. Content such as images, videos, or text and buttons that users use to promote their content, subscribe to content creators, or subscribe to our posts. If the users are members of the platform Twitter, Twitter can call the o.g. Assign contents and functions to the profiles of the users there. Twitter is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active)).  
Privacy Policy: <https://twitter.com/privacy>[  
](https://twitter.com/privacy)Opt-Out: <https://twitter.com/personalization>.

#### Instagram

Within our online offering, features and content of the Instagram service offered by Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA, may be incorporated. For this, e.g. Content such as images, videos, or text and buttons that users use to promote their content, subscribe to the content creators, or subscribe to our posts. If the users are members of the platform Instagram, Instagram can call the o.g. Assign contents and functions to the profiles of the users there.  
Privacy policy: <http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/>.

#### Pinterest

Within our online offering, features and content of the Pinterest service offered by Pinterest Inc., 635 High Street, Palo Alto, CA, 94301, USA, may be incorporated. For this, e.g. Content such as images, videos, or text and buttons that users use to promote their content, subscribe to the content creators, or subscribe to our posts. If the users are members of the platform Pinterest, Pinterest can call the o.g. Assign contents and functions to the profiles of the users there.  
Privacy Policy: <https://about.pinterest.com/privacy-policy.>

#### LinkedIn

Within our online offering, features and content of the LinkedIn service offered by inkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland, may be incorporated. For this, e.g. Content such as images, videos, or text and buttons that users use to promote their content, subscribe to content creators, or subscribe to our posts. If the users are members of the platform LinkedIn, LinkedIn can call the o.g. Assign contents and functions to the profiles of the users there. LinkedIn privacy statement: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy. LinkedIn is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000L0UZAA0&status=active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000L0UZAA0&status=active)).  
Privacy Policy: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>,  
Opt-out: <https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out>.

[Created with Datenschutz-Generator.de by RA Dr. med. Thomas Schwenke](https://datenschutz-generator.de/)
